This video has been sped up by 2x as the simualtion was run for 10 mins as it was running very slow
The command used to launch the simulation was 'ros2 launch solution solution_nav2_launch.py random_seed:=0
To start of with the robot's initial positions are set for the nav2 pose estimation
The robots now look for the nearest item and head towards it
Notice the balls on rviz are a visualisation of the nearest item of each colour that the robot can see
The items wont match the position properly as they are where the robot thinks the item is.
Sometimes there are odities in the visualisation (such as 2 or 0 items of the same colour). This is due to the item regonistion flickering.
Robot 2 (bottom right) missed the item it was aiming for and can no longer see any items so heads home to try again
It Then accidentally drives through an item, picking it up
Robot 3 (top right) has now picked up the green but sees an item of higher value and so is targetting that
Robot 1 (bottom left) found a blue and since there are no higher value items heads stright home
Robot 2 sees an item so heads towards it but then see a closer item so priortises that
There is no attempt made by robot 3 to avoid the green when holding a blue
Robot 2 collects the green and can see no items of higher value to goes home
Robot 2 then sees a blue so targets that instead
Robot 1 sees an item so targets it
The nearest starting position for robot 2 is taken so it targets the next nearest
Robot 3 keeps updating is target for what it views as the nearest
Robot 2 and 3 got too close to each other so are both sent to a start position
Robot 1 sees a blue so targets it, loses sight of it but carries on towards it and then still cant see it so gives up and goes home
Robots 1 and 3 got too close so are sent to starting positions, the one for robot 1 is far away so that they hopefully go away from each other